<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Root xmlns:aid="http://ns.adobe.com/AdobeInDesign/4.0/" xmlns:aid5="http://ns.adobe.com/AdobeInDesign/5.0/"><h1>Character Creation</h1>
<h2>Choose a Specialty</h2>
<p>Look at the list of specialties and choose one that interests you. Your Inquisitor's retinue doesn't need two of the same type of class, so if two people want the same class talk it over like adults and compromise. Your character will be able to unlock new specialities as they level up.</p>

<blockquote class="first-person">I want to look for clues and interrogate people, so I'll pick Investigator.</blockquote>

<h2>Choose a Background</h3>
<p>Your background describes what your character was doing before being recruited by your Inquisitor. It might not have been where your skills brought you to the attention of the Inquisitor, but it is likely. Once per session you may reroll a roll if you can describe how your background would have prepared you for this situation, using the This I Know special move.</p>

<ul class="options">
<li>Adeptus Administratrum</li>
<li>Adeptus Arbites</li>
<li>Adeptus Mechanicus</li>
<li>Ecclesiarchy</li>
<li>Imperial Guard</li>
<li>Outcast</li>
</ul>

<blockquote class="first-person">I'd like to have a religious background as someone who grew up working in a Basilica. I'll choose Ecclesiarchy.</blockquote>

<h2>Assign Your Stats</h2>
<p>You get the following stats to assign to your character: -1, -1, 0, 0, 0, +1, +1, +2. Assign each one to one of the following characteristics.</p>

<h2>Choose a Home World</h2>
<p>Your Home World will give one special move and allow you to increase one of your stats.</p>

<h3>Death World</h3>
<p>Planet where everything wants to kill you.</p>
<p><strong>World Move:</strong> Death World characters gain +1 on all Last Breath rolls.</p>
<p><strong>Choose one:</strong> +1 Agility or +1 Toughness, to a max of +2.</p>
<h3>Feral World</h3>
<p>A planet with very little technology.</p>
<p><strong>World Move:</strong> Feral World characters +1 piercing when using primitive weapons.</p>
<p><strong>Choose one:</strong> +1 Strength or +1 Toughness, to a max of +2.</p>
<h3>Forge World</h3>
<p>Manufactorums cover the landscape.</p>
<p><strong>World Move:</strong> Forge World characters replace one of their d6s with a d8 when rolling Tech-Use.</p>
<p><strong>Choose one:</strong> +1 Intelligence or +1 Toughness, to a max of +2.</p>
<h3>Highborn</h3>
<p>You are the member of a noble house, or powerful family.</p>
<p><strong>World Move:</strong> Highborn characters gain +1 to any Defy Danger or Parley rolls that involve talking to members of the Imperium.</p>
<p><strong>Choose one:</strong> +1 Fellowship or +1 Intelligence, to a max of +2.</p>
<h3>Hive World</h3>
<p>Hab blocks and cityscape cover much of this planet.</p>
<p><strong>World Move:</strong> Hive World characters gain +1 to any Defy Danger rolls when moving through crowds.</p>
<p><strong>Choose one:</strong> +1 Agility or +1 Perception, to a max of +2.</p>
<h3>Shrine World</h3>
<p>This world is dedicated to the veneration of the God-Emperor and his saints.</p>
<p><strong>World Move:</strong> Shrine World characters can reroll any double 1s result once per session.</p>
<p><strong>Choose one:</strong> +1 Fellowship or +1 Willpower, to a max of +2.</p>
<h3>Voidborn</h3>
<p>You were born in the cold of space aboard a ship.</p>
<p><strong>World Move:</strong> Voidborn gain +1 to any rolls to resist warp energy.</p>
<p><strong>Choose one:</strong> +1 Intelligence or +1 Willpower, to a max of +2.</p>

<h2>Modify Your Stats</h2>
<p>Change one of your stats based on the bonus offered by your Home World.</p>

<h2>Set Your Max Wounds</h2>
<p>Your max wounds is equal to 4. If your Toughness is positive, add that as well.</p>

<h2>Choose a Name</h2>
<p>Select a name for your character. Make something up on your own or roll on the tables below to inspire you.</p>

<table class="table table-striped"><thead>
<tr>
<th align="left">d8</th>
<th align="left">Male</th>
<th align="left">Female</th>
<th align="left">Nickname</th>
</tr>
</thead><tbody>
<tr><td>1</td><td>Gaius</td><td>Ellyn</td><td>Shiv</td></tr>
<tr><td>2</td><td>Bragg</td><td>Fernanda</td><td>Grimshine</td></tr>
</tbody></table>

<blockquote class="first-person">I'd like to go by a nickname, but I'm not sure what I want so I'll roll on the table. I rolled a 7 so I'll go by Carver.</blockquote></Root>