<h1>Damage and Wounds</h1>
<p>This document is a work in progress. All numbers, and the entire system, are subject to change.</p>

<h2>Damage</h2>
<ul>
  <li>Damage is given by people, environment, weapons, poison, etc</li>
  <li>Damage is not guaranteed to inflict wounds</li>
  <li>Whether damage inflicts a wound depends on your defense</li>
</ul>

<h2>Wounds</h2>
<ul>
  <li>A creature has a certain number of max wounds they can take before they die</li>
  <li>A wound is significant damage, not just scrapes and bruises</li>
  <li>Wounds can be healed, but can easily leave scars</li>
  <li>reatures have Current Wounds and Max Wounds</li>
</ul>

<h2>Defense</h2>
<ul>
  <li>Your Defense is a number that represents your ability to withstand damage without suffering wounds</li>
  <li>It’s a single tally that incorporates things like armor, reflexes, cover, shields, and even luck, or faith.</li>
  <li>Your Defense can change from attack to attack based on your physical state, the type of attack, your surroundings, etc</li>
</ul>


<h2>Dealing Damage and Inflicting Wounds</h2>
<ul>
  <li>When you deal damage, you roll all the relevant dice of your weapon, as well as any bonus dice afforded to you from moves, equipment, or buffs</li>
  <li>After you have rolled your dice, you may roll extra dice or reroll some dice based on special rules you have</li>
  <li>Once you are done rolling, count all the dice that are higher than the Defense of your target</li>
  <li>That number is how many wounds you inflict</li>
</ul>

<h2>Taking Damage and Suffering Wounds</h2>
<ul>
  <li>This works the same as Dealing and Inflicting but in reverse</li>
  <li>Roll the dice for the damage you are receiving</li>
  <li>Reroll any dice or extra dice as needed</li>
  <li>Count the number of dice that are higher than your Defense</li>
  <li>That number is how many wounds you suffer</li>
</ul>

<h2>Example of Play</h2>
<ul>
  <li>Griff shoots his shotgun at a cultist named Scar</li>
  <li>Griff’s shotgun deals 2d6 damage and has the tag Proven (2)</li>
  <li>Griff rolls his damage and gets a 1 and a 3</li>
  <li>The Proven (2) tag lets Griff reroll any roll of 2 or lower, but not the reroll</li>
  <li>Griff rerolls his 1 and gets a 5</li>
  <li>Griff’s final result is a 5 and a 3</li>
  <li>The cultist has a defense of 3</li>
  <li>Griff causes 1 wound to Scar</li>
</ul>

<h2>Example Wounds and Defense</h2>
<p>A human with civilian clothes and no training or combat experience would have Max Wounds of 3 and Defense of 1</p>
<p>An Imperial Guardsman wearing Flak Armor would have Defense 3 and Max Wounds 3</p>
<p>An Adeptus Astartes with Power Armor would have Defense 6 and Max Wounds 8</p>

<h2>Dying</h2>
<p>When your current wounds reaches or exceeds your max wounds, you are dying and roll for {{move last_breath}}. Some dangers instantly have you roll for {{move last_breath}}, completely bypassing damage and wounds.</p>

<h2>Improving Defense</h2>
<p>Here are some things that can improve defense.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Flak Armor: +1 Defense</li>
  <li>Good cover: +1 Defense against ranged attacks</li>
  <li>Parry skill: +1 Defense against melee attacks</li>
  <li>Power armor: +2 Defense</li>
  <li>Adeptus power armor: +3 Defense</li>
  <li>Uncanny reflexes: +1 Defense</li>
</ul>

<h2>Healing Wounds</h2>
<ul>
  <li>You can reduce your wounds by 1 or by getting medical attention</li>
  <li>One day of rest will reduce your current wounds by 1</li>
  <li>One day of rest under the care of a talented medical team will reduce your current wounds by 2</li>
  <li>A medkit applied properly will heal 1 wound</li>
</ul>

